[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Now that we've seen that the log can be an important function,
والآن بعد أن رأينا كيف أن اللوغاريتم يمكن أن يكون وظيفة مهمة،
when applied to the likelihood ensure that we're going to have to express in terms
عند تطبيقه على الاحتمال تأكد أنه سيتعين علينا التعبير من حيث
of the log likelihood computer gradient.
تدرج حساب لوغاريتم الاحتمال.
This continues to be part of that very,
وما زال هذا جزءًا من المشتق
very optional PhD level only derivation that we're doing here.
الخياري بشكل كبير ذي مستوى الدكتوراه فقط الذي نجريه هنا.
Now let's revisit the likelihood function that we discussed and
الآن دعونا نعيد النظر إلى دالة الاحتمال التي ناقشناها
see how the log plays a role.
ونرى كيف يلعب اللوغاريتم دورًا.
So the key here is that the log of the sum is the sum of the logs that we discussed.
لذا المفتاح هنا هو أن لوغاريتم المجموع هو مجموع اللوغاريتمات التي ناقشناها.
And in our case, if you have the log of the product
وفي حالتنا، إذا كانت لدينا لوغاريتم ناتج
of i equals 1 through N of some function,
i يساوي 1 عبر N لبعض الدوال،
let's call it Fi, then that is equal to the sum
لنطلق عليها Fi، ثم يكون هذا مساويًا لمجموع
of i equals one through N of the log of Fi.
i مساويًا 1 عبر N لوغاريتم Fi.
So, the log of the product is the sum of the logs.
لذلك، يكون لوغاريتم الناتج هو مجموعة اللوغاريتمات.
And so, in our case, what we're going to get is the log
وهكذا، في حالتنا، ما سنحصل عليه هو دالة
likelihood function is going to be the sum of i = 1 through n
لوغاريتم الاحتمال وهو سيكون مجموع i = 1 عبر n
of the log of the probability of yi, given xi and w.
لوغاريتم احتمالية yi، من خلال قيمة xi وw.
Now, if you're thinking about derivatives, you'll see exactly why the log was useful.
والآن، إذا كنت تفكر بشأن المشتقات، سترى بالضبط سبب أن اللوغاريتم كان مفيدًا.
The derivative of products is really a complicated thing, but once we've taken
مشتق النواتج هو أمر معقد للغاية، ولكن بمجرد أن نأخذ
the log, the derivative of the sum is just the sum of the derivative.
اللوغاريتم، يكون مشتق المجموع هو مجموع المشتق فقط.
And so that's going to simplify all the math that we have to do.
وهكذا سيبسط ذلك جميع العمليات الرياضية التي يعين علينا إجراؤها.
And that's the core reason that we take the log.
وذلك هو السبب الرئيسي وراء قيامنا بأخذ اللوغاريتم.
There's a few other technical reasons, but that's one very important one.
هناك بضعة أسباب فنية أخرى، ولكن ذلك هو سبب مهم للغاية.
Okay, so that was trick number one.
حسنًا، كان ذلك الحيلة الأولى.
Take the log.
أخذ اللوغاريتم.
Trick number two is to introduce indicator functions just like we showed
الحيلة الثانية هي تقديم دوال المؤشر تمامًا مثلما وضحنا
in the derivative that we had before.
في المشتق الذي تناولناه سابقًا.
So, if we take the log likelihood function.
لذلك، إذا أخذنا دالة لوغاريتم الاحتمال.
So, this is the sum of the log with the probability of yi given xi and w.
حسنًا، يكون هذا مجموع لوغاريتم احتمالية yi من خلال قيمة xi وw.
That can be written as the sum of two terms.
ويمكن كتابة ذلك في صورة مجموع حدين.
The indicator that yi is +1 has the probability of yi=+1,
لدى المؤشر أن yi تساوي +1 احتمالية أن yi=+1،
plus the indicative y is -1 has the probability of y=-1.
زائد المؤشر أن yi تساوي -1 احتمالية أن y=-1.
So in other words, if it's,
لذا بعبارة أخرى، إذا كان
if yi=+1 then the first term comes to play and
إذا كانت yi=+1 فعندئذ يدخل أول حد في الاعتبار
the second term becomes zero.
ويصبح الحد الثاني صفرًا.
But if YI is equal to minus one,
ولكن إذا كان YI تساوي سالب واحد،
then the first term becomes zero, then the second term becomes active.
فعندئذ يصبح الحد الأول صفرًا، ثم يصبح الحد الثاني نشطًا.
And so we see that because of this, we get exactly the equation above.
والآن نرى أنه بسبب هذا نحصل بالضبط على المعادلة أعلاه.
But, the indicators are going to make our life a lot simpler
ولكن، ستجعل المؤشرات حياتنا أبسط بكثير
throughout the derivatives and all of the operations that we need to do.
عبر المشتقات وجميع العمليات التي نحتاج إلى إجرائها.
Here is an interesting thing.
وفيما يلي شيء مثير للاهتمام.
So far we've only talked about the probability y = +1, but
وحتى الآن لقد تحدثنا فقط بشأن الاحتمالية y = +1، لكن
in this equation we have the probability y = -1.
في هذه المعادلة، يكون لدينا الاحتمالية y = -1.
Interesting.
الاهتمام.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]